A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 10 FA1318
Rockefeller Archive Center
National Committee on United States-China Relations records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 10
1967-2008
Rockefeller Archive Center
National Committee on United States-China Relations
FA1318
6.55 Cubic Feet 7 record storage boxes, 181 Audio reels, 49 videos
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: Series 1: Audio recordings. Series 2: Video recordings.
Scope and Contents
Audiovisual recordings of conferences, seminars, symposia, and NCUSCR programs, events and exhanges.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Biographical / Historical
The National Committee on United States – China Relations (NCUSCR) was established in 1966 as a nonprofit educational organization with a mission to encourage mutual understanding and dialogue between citizens of the United States and China. The National Committee came into being through the cooperative efforts of scholars and civic, religious, and business leaders who, at a time of mutual hostility between the two countries, sought to stimulate public discussion about China and the United States' relations with it by sponsoring conferences, seminars, publications, and other education and outreach programs. In 1972, the National Committee sponsored the Chinese table tennis team's historic U. S. visit. This round of "Ping Pong Diplomacy," which followed closely on Richard Nixon's visit to China in February 1972, helped pave the way for later exchanges and, eventually, for the normalization of relations with China in 1979. Building on these cultural exchanges, the National Committee came to be a primary organizer of professional and policy exchanges between the two countries (and including Hong Kong and Taiwan), in the areas of foreign affairs and international relations, economic development, governance and legal affairs, education, mass media, environmental and global issues, etc. As its role in exchanges became more prominent, the National Committee turned over some of its educational programs to the Asia Society in the late 1970s, but it continues its educational role through public education events and ongoing outreach. Funding for the National Committee comes from the United States government (especially the Department of State), corporations, and foundations, as well as from its individual membership.
Sound recordings; Moving Images
- Audio Recordings, 1967-2004; 1; All items are 1/4 inch audio tape unless otherwise noted.
  Arrangement
  Series 1: Audio Recordings is arranged in 5 subseries as follows:
  Subseries A: China Conversations
  Subseries B: Conversations from Wingspread
  Subseries C: Conferences, Seminars, Lectures, and Meetings
  Subseries D: United States - China Dialogues
  Subseries E: America - China Society.
  Tapes have been minimally arranged chronologically by date of creation.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  Scope and Contents
  Interviews, conferences, events, panel discussions, and presentations.
  General
  All titles are currently based on original container annotations.
  - China Conversations, 1968-1975; A
    The China Conversations tape program was an early National Committee project. From 1967 to 1975 (or later), staff member Arlene Posner conducted interviews with China scholars, journalists, recent visitors, and other individuals knowledgeable on China or U. S. – China relations. The half-hour recordings cover topics ranging from family life, health, education, agriculture, medicine, and culture, to the political situation and China's foreign relations. The series contained at least 28 titles, which were available for loan to schools, radio stations, or other outlets, or were packaged and distributed by educational publishers.
    Some of the recordings carry approximate dates, as some interviews were reissued. For several interviews there is both a "long" version and an abbreviated, "short" version of the recording.
    - China's Traditional Past: An Interview with Benjamin I. Schwartz, 1972 October 17; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8858)
      Access copy available.
      China Conversations
    - China's Historical Tradition and Social Institutions: An interview with Franz Michael, circa 1970s; 24 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8859)
    - Political Control and Social Re-Organization in Communist China: An interview with A. Doak Barnett, circa 1970s; 26 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8860)
    - Social Reorganization in China: An interview with Ezra Vogel, circa 1970s; 27 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8861)
    - Communist China's Nuclear Power: An interview with Dwight H. Perkins, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8862)
    - China's Pattern of Behavior in a Nuclear Environment: An interview with Alice Langley Hsieh, circa 1970s; 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8863)
    - Communist China's Military Doctrine and its Concept of Military Organization: An interview with Ralph Powell, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8865)
    - Sino-Soviet Relations: An interview with Harrison Salisbury (Long version), circa 1970s; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8866)
    - Sino-Soviet Relations: An interview with Harrison Salisbury (Short version), circa 1970s; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8867)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Low volume
    - Sino-Soviet Relations: An interview with George Ginsburgs (Long version), circa 1970s; 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8868)
    - Sino-Soviet Relations: An interview with George Ginsburgs (Short version), circa 1970s; 5 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8869)
    - Chinese Foreign Policy toward the Third World: An interview with Robert A. Scalapino, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8870)
    - China's Foreign Policy: Its Implications for the Future: An Interview with Richard L. Walker, circa 1970s; ¼ inch audio tape; 28 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15492)
    - Recent U.S. Government Policy Initiatives toward China: An Interview with Paul Kreisberg, 1970 May 5; 28 minutes 19 seconds; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9007)
      Same content as AV 8873 and AV 8872. No skip in announcement of Kreisberg's name.
      Tape labeled Kreisberg #1.
    - Recent U.S. Government Policy Initiatives toward China: An Interview with Paul Kreisberg (Short version), 1970 May 5; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8871)
    - China's Historic Relations with Southeast Asia: An Interview with Claude A. Buss, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8874)
    - Chinese-Japanese Relations: An interview with Edwin O. Reischauer (Long Version), circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8875)
      Low volume at beginning of interview.
    - Chinese-Japanese Relations: An Interview with Edwin O. Reischauer, circa 1972; 16 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8915)
    - Personal Observations from a Recent Visitor to China: An Interview with Colin McCullough (Long version), 1970 March 3; 26 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8878)
    - Personal Observations from a Recent Visitor to China: An Interview with Colin McCullough (Short version), 1970 March 3; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8876)
    - Trade with China: Personal Observations from a Canadian Businessman: An interview with Pat Clever (Long version), circa 1970s; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8880)
    - Trade with China: Personal Observations from a Canadian Businessman: An interview with Pat Clever (Short version), circa 1970s; 7 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8879)
      Program begins at 31 seconds.
    - A Recent Trip to China: An interview with Pat Clever (Long version), 1970 October 17; 22 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8881)
    - A Recent Trip to China: An interview with Pat Clever (Short version), circa 1970s; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8882)
    - Prospects for U.S.-China Trade: An interview with Robert F. Dernberger (Long version), 1970 April 23; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8884)
    - Prospects for U.S.-China Trade: An interview with Robert F. Dernberger (Short version), 1970 April 23; 7 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8883)
    - The Sino-Soviet Conflict: An Interview with Donald S. Zagoria, circa 1969; 24 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8885)
    - Cultural Revolution: An Interview with Donald Klein and Harald Munthe-Kaas, circa 1968; ¼ inch audio tape; 27 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15493)
      Donald Klein interview of Harald Munthe-Kaas, with an introduction by Arlene Posner.
    - Aftermath of the Cultural Revolution: An Interview with Harald Munthe-Kaas, circa 1968; ¼ inch audio tape; 32 minutes 03 seconds. (Box 13, Reel AV 15499)
    - Aftermath of the Cultural Revolution: An Interview with Harald Munthe-Kaas, circa 1968; 7 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9012)
      Tape labeled Munthe-Kaas #5. China Conversations.
    - Ideology and Politics: An Interview with Lucian Pye, circa 1968; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8887)
    - Political and Social Trends in Taiwan: An Interview with Fox Butterfield (Long version), 1970 May 18; 32 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8889)
    - Political and Social Trends in Taiwan: An Interview with Fox Butterfield (Short version), 1970 May 18; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8888)
    - China and the United Nations: An Interview with Elmore Jackson, circa 1970s; 27 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8890)
    - Is Taiwan an Obstacle to U.S.-China Relations? An Interview with Edward Friedman, 1971 March 5; 21 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8892)
    - Hostage in Peking: An Interview with Anthony Grey, 1971 March 10; 31 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8893)
    - U.S.-China Relations: An Interview with Dr. George Taylor, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 8894)
    - U.S.-China Relations: An Interview with A. Doak Barnett, circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8895)
    - China's Problems and Future Prospects in the Post-Mao Period: An interview with A. Doak Barnett (Unedited), circa 1974 - 1975; 36 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8922)
    - United States Policy toward China: An Interview with James C. Thomson Jr., circa 1970s; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8897)
    - The Taiwan Factor in America's China Policy - U.S. Government View: An Interview with Thomas P. Shoesmith, 1971 April 29; 22 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8898)
    - Does the U.S. Have Moral Obligations to Taiwan? An Interview with Mark Mancall, 1971 March 5; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8906)
    - A Western Correspondent in China: An Interview with Norman Webster, 1971 October 18; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8899)
      Recording has persistent audio buzz.
    - Chinese Foreign Policy Since the Cultural Revolution: An Interview with David Mozingo, 1971 October 18; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8900)
    - Child Care in China: An Interview with Ruth Sidel, circa 1972; 32 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8901)
    - The Functions and Nature of Education in China: An Interview with Donald J. Munro, 1972 October 26; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8902)
    - Youth in China: An Interview with Ronald N. Montaperto, circa 1974-1975; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8907)
    - An American Correspondent in China: An Interview with Tillman Durdin, 1971 June 7; 39 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8908)
    - Organization and Development of Science: An Interview with Richard P. Suttmeier, circa 1974-1975; 36 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8909)
    - Maoist Man - The Individual and Society: An Interview with Benjamin I. Schwartz, circa 1970s; 26 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8910)
    - Comrade Chiang Ch'ing: An Interview with Roxane Witke, circa 1974-1975; 27 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8912)
      China Conversations. Comrade Chiang Ch'ing was the title of the book Witke based on her interviews with Jiang Qing (Madame Mao).
    - Agricultural Development in China: An Interview with Dwight H. Perkins, circa 1970s; 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13, Reel AV 8914)
      Audio has persistent buzz throughout.
    - China Revisited: An Interview with John K. Fairbank, 1972 May 23; 18 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8916)
    - Art and Archaeology in China, circa 1975; 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8917)
      China Conversations. Narration to accompany slide set on Chinese Art and Archaeology: An Introduction. Created in conjunction with the Chinese Archaeology exhibit.
    - Chinese Archaeology: An Interview with K. C. Chang, 1975; 27 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8918)
    - China's Attitude toward Religion: An Interview with Donald E. MacInnis, circa 1974-1975; 23 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8919)
    - China's Changing Relations with Europe: An Interview with Dick Wilson, circa 1974-1975; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8920)
    - Chinese Foreign Policy toward the Third World: An Interview with Peter Van Ness, circa 1974-1975; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8921)
    - Some Observations on China's Population: An Interview with Leo A. Orleans (Unedited), circa 1974-1975; 53 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8923)
      China Conversations.
    - Medicine and Public Health: An Interview with Victor Sidel, 1972 December 5; ¼ inch audio tape; 29 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15495)
    - The Position of Women in China: An Interview with Chen Yaunchi, 1972 May 30; ¼ inch audio tape; 23 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15497)
    - The Role of the Mass Media in China: An Interview with Gerald Tannebaum, circa 1972; ¼ inch audio tape; 27 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15496)
  - Conversations from Wingspread, 1972-1975; B
    Conversations from Wingspread was a series of half-hour audio conversations with scholars and specialists on various subjects, which in the case of the NCUSCR collection pertain specifically to China and U.S. – China relations.
    Moderated by Dan Price, the programs often addressed topics that similarly formed the subject of conferences at the Johnson Foundation's Wingspread Conference Center, in Racine, WI.
    The individual programs were numbered; the notes include the recording number (e.g., R-3) when it is known.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - United States-China Cultural Exchanges, 1972; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8935)
      Program R-3. Discussion with Rhoads Murphey, Louise Bennett, and Robert Aylward, moderated by Leslie Paffrath.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - United States-China Cultural Exchanges, 1972; 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8934)
      Program R-4. Conversation with Daniel Tretiak, William Wu, and Alexander Eckstein, moderated by Leslie Paffrath.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - Education in China, 1973; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8933)
      Program R-43. Discussion by Susan Shirk, Michel Oksenberg, and Changdu Hu, moderated by Dan Price.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - China after the Cultural Revolution, 1975; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8932)
      Program R-46. Conversation with Alexander Casella, Douglas P. Murray, and Phillips Talbot, moderated by Dan Price.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - Science Policy in the People's Republic of China, 1973; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8931)
      Program R-55. Conversation with Herbert Simon, Richard Suttmeier, and Raphael Tsu. Dan Price, moderator.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - A Visit to China, 1973; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8930)
      Program R-56. Discussion of scientific and other developments in the People's Republic of China, with Jesse C. H. Hwa, Harry Harding, Jr., and Chen-Ning Yang. Dan Price, moderator.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - Health Care in the People's Republic of China (1), 1973; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8929)
      Program R-91. Discussion with Ruth Watson Lubic, George I. Lithcott, and Myron E. Wegman, on their Medical Delegation trip to China. Moderated by Dan Price.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - Health Care in the People's Republic of China (2), 1973; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8928)
      Program R-92. Interview with Doctors Herbert Adams, Jack Geiger, and Mitchell Spellman, on their recent visits to China. Moderated by Dan Price.
    - Conversations from Wingspread - One of the World's Most Influential Women: A Profile of Madame Mao, circa 1974; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 9, Reel AV 8927)
      Program R-142. Dan Price interview with Roxane Witke, concerning her 60 hours of interviews with Jiang Qing (Madame Mao) in 1972.
  - Conferences, Seminars, Lectures, and Meetings, 1967-2004; C
    This subseries contains recorded proceedings of several National Committee conferences and seminars, including its 1969 Convocation on the U.S. and China, some of its early seminars for journalists, and various conferences held at the Johnson Foundation's Wingspread Conference Center. It also includes recordings of a few NCUSCR members meetings, annual addresses, and various other lectures or talks. In addition, the subseries contains the recording of a 1973 education delegation's meetings in China, as well as briefing meetings for the State Education Leaders delegation in 1977-1978.
    - Dr. Robert A. Scalapino: Communist China, 1967 April 13; 58 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8926)
      Lecture at Fort Leavenworth, KS. Tape labeled "Tape 1 of 2." A second tape, recording a question and answer period, has not been found.
    - Journalists Seminar, Harvard University, 1967 July 13-15?; 1/4 inch audio tape; 4 hours, 17 minutes (Box 11, Reel AV 9006)
      Regional Journalists. Seminar organized by the Harvard Field Staff. First day of meetings.
    - Journalists Seminar, Harvard University, 1967 July 13-15?; 1/4 inch audio tape; 5 hours, 11 minutes (Box 11, Reel AV 9005)
      Regional Journalists. Seminar organized by the Harvard Field Staff. Second day of meetings.
    - Harald Munthe-Kaas Speech, 1968 January 29; 1/4 inch audio tape; 37 minutes (Box 12, Reel AV 9018)
      Address on the cultural revolution, probably given in Detroit or Ann Arbor.
    - Harald Munthe-Kaas - NCUSCR Community Leaders Seminar, 1968 February 5; 1/4 inch audio tape; 78 minutes (Box 12, Reel AV 9019)
      Introduction by Cecil Thomas. Address given in New York to 40 community leaders, representing national organizations.
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Tape 1 of 5, 1968 February 29; 169 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9024)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Richard Solomon, "The Cultural Revolution"; Mark Gayn, "China, A First-Hand View."
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Tape 2 of 5, 1968 February 29; 194 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9025)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Roy Hofheinz, "Social Change and Communist Power"; discussion period; evening roundtable on Public Health (Dr. Kenneth Thomson and others).
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Tape 3 of 5, 1968 February 29 - March 1; 194 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9026)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Conclusion of Public Health discussion; Jurgen Domes, "The Cultural Revolution and the Army"; Harold Hinton, "Development of China's Foreign Policy"; Dwight Perkins, "China's Economic Development and Military Potential."
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Tape 4 of 5, 1968 March 1; 69 minutes (followed by 125 minutes of blank recording).; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9027)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Conclusion of Dwight Perkins discussion; Richard Walker, "The Nature of CCP Social Control."
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Tape 5 of 5, 1968 March 2; 163 minutes (the program begins at 11:00 minutes).; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9028)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Loren Fessler, "Problems Facing the Western Journalist Reporting from Hong Kong"; Donald Klein, round table chair, "Communicating about China: An Exchange on Problems Confronting Scholars and Journalists." Presentation by Paul Kreisberg ("United States-China Relations: Present Problems and Future Prospects") not on this recording.
    - China Seminar for Southern Journalists - Banquet, 1968 March 1; 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12, Reel AV 9020)
      Atlanta (Regional Journalists seminar). Address by Robert Scalapino on "China in Historical Perspective."
    - Senatorial Assistants Program - Address by Lt. Gen. Wang Sheng and Professor Cheng Hsueh-chia, 1968 May 7; 1/4 inch audio tape; 59 minutes (Box 12, Reel AV 9021)
      Address (in Chinese, with English translation) entitled, "An Analysis of the Chinese Communist Army: A View from Taiwan." Luncheon program at the Capital Hill Hotel, Washington, DC.
    - David Mozingo - Foundation Seminar, New York, 1968 June 11; 1/4 inch audio tape; 75 minutes (Box 12, Reel AV 9023)
      Continuing seminar on China, sponsored by the Christopher Reynolds Foundation and the NCUSCR. Mozingo spoke on the Balance of Power in Asia.
    - "Background" Program 25 - Professor Whiting, 1969 February 25; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8936)
      Alan S. Whiting, professor of Political Science, University of Michigan.
    - "Background" Program 27 - Professor Alexander Eckstein, 1969 March 11; 30 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 10, Reel AV 8937)
      Background: A Program of Comment, Conversation, and Analysis. Produced by T. R. [Tom Ricci?] for the University of Michigan Broadcasting Service.
    - Convocation on the U.S. and China (1), 1969 March 20; 33 minutes (Box 10, Reel AV 8939)
      National Convocation on the U. S. and China - The Next Decade. Introductory panel - presentations by Richard Walker, Daivd Oancia, Richard Pfeffer.
      Material Specific Details
      1/4 inch audio tape
    - Convocation on the U.S. and China (2), 1969 March 20; 1/4 inch audio tape; 32 minutes (Box 10, Reel AV 8940)
      National Convocation on the U. S. and China - The Next Decade. Continuation of introductory panel - presentations by Richard Pfeffer (continued), Rod MacFarquhar, and Paul Kreisberg.
    - Convocation on the U.S. and China (3), 1969 March 20; ¼ inch audio tape; 9 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15501)
    - Convocation on the U.S. and China (4), 1969 March 20; ¼ inch audio tape; 32 minutes (Box 13, Reel AV 15502)
      National Convocation on the U.S. and China - The Next Decade. Luncheon address by Jacob Javits.